(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-28T08:56:43.977840",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
遥か空 響いてる祈りは奇跡に
Prayers echoing in the distant skies become miracles,
真夜中の青にとけて
Dissolving into the blue midnight,
流れてく涙のつぶ
teardrops flow away.
迷いなく 包み込む
Without hesitation, wrapped
温もりに 出会った
in the warmth I found.
真っ白な雪のように
Like pure white snow,
どこまでも素直な言葉
with words honest and pure everywhere,
鉄の羽まとった
you move my steel-winged self
僕を動かしていく
forward.
傷つくたびに
Every time I get hurt,
優しくなれる
I become kinder.
君のその笑顔だけ
I want to protect your smile
守りぬきたい
above all else.
願いは一つ
That is my one wish.
時を越え刻まれた 悲しみの記憶
Memories of sorrow carved across time,
真っ直ぐに受け止める 君は光の天使
accepted straight on—you are an angel of light.
あの日胸に灯った 永遠の炎
The eternal flame lit in my chest that day
深い闇解き放たれて
released from the deep darkness,
自由の扉開いてく
opening the door to freedom.
強く果てない未来へ
Toward a strong, endless future.
冷たい緑の月に 映し出す心の影
The shadow of my heart reflected on the cold green moon,
寂しげに呟いた “君のそばにいたい”
murmured lonely: "I want to stay by your side."
真実と向き合うこと 教えてくれた勇気は
The courage you gave me to face the truth
僕を駆け巡って 夢に目覚めていく
courses through me, awakening my dreams.
触れ合う気持ち 離れないように
So our touching feelings never part,
しっかりと抱きしめて
holding each other tight,
確かな想い 貫いていく
carrying our unwavering feelings through.
銀の海に隠した 空白のページ
A blank page hidden in the silver sea—
君だけが知っている “本当”を見せて
show me the "truth" that only you know.
吹き荒れる切なさに 生まれ行く誓い
An oath born from raging sorrow—
もう何も恐くはないよ 結んだ視線そらさずに
I'm no longer afraid, with our gazes locked.
大切な「今」始める
Our precious "now" begins.
君が君でいられる場所
A place where you can be yourself,
幻にされないように
undisturbed by illusions,
消えない雨の苦しみも
and the pain of never-ending rain.
鍵を壊してぶつけてよ
Break the key and throw it,
隣にいるから 全てを信じて
since I'm right beside you, believing in everything.
時を越え刻まれた 悲しみの記憶
Memories of sorrow carved across time,
真っ直ぐに受け止める 君は光の天使
accepted straight on—you are an angel of light.
あの日胸に灯った 永遠の炎
The eternal flame lit in my chest that day
深い闇解き放たれて
released from the deep darkness,
自由の扉開いてく
opening the door to freedom.
強く果てない未来へ
Toward a strong, endless future.
そう、きっとここから始まる…
Yes, it starts right here...
遥か天空 響いている
Echoing in the distant skies,
祈りは奇跡に
prayers become miracles.
夜中の青にとけて流れていく 涙の粒
My flowing teardrops dissolve into the blue midnight.
迷いなく包み込む 温もりに 出会った
Without question, I met a warmth that enveloped me.
真っ白な雪のように どこまでも素直な言葉
As pure as white snow, honest words anywhere,
鉄の羽纏った 僕を動かしている
moving me who am clad in steel wings.
傷くたびに優しくなれる 君のその笑顔だけ守り抜きたい
The more I'm hurt, the kinder I become; I want to protect only your smile.
願いはひとつ 時を越え 刻まれた悲しみの記憶
My one wish: memories of sorrow engraved across time.
真っ直ぐに受け止める 君は光の天使
You, who face them straight on, are an angel of light.
あの日 胸に灯った 永遠の炎
The eternal flame lit in my chest that day,
深い闇解き放て 自由の扉 開いてく
releasing deep darkness and opening the door to freedom.
強く 果てない未来へ
Toward a strong, endless future.
お待たせみんな！
Sorry to keep you waiting, everyone!
今年もポルカの誕生日が始まったー！
Polka's birthday has started again this year!
タイトルはかっこいい「Glitter Love」ということで、
The title is the cool "Glitter Love",
尾丸ポルカ生誕祭2026でいっぱい呟いてね！
and please tweet a lot with #OmaruPolkaBirthday2026!
今回は全部がまず愛と勇気と戦う女の子になってます！
This time, it's all about girls fighting with love and courage!
そして、見てくださいこのステージ！
And look at this stage!
はあ！
Whoa!
すごい広い！
It's so huge!
おお！なんとですね広いんですけどまずスクリーンが超絶大迫力！
Whoa! It's so huge, and the screen is super impactful!
なんとなくいつもの3倍くらい頑張りました！いや頑張ってもらいました！ありがとうございます！
We worked about three times harder than usual! Well, they worked hard for me! Thank you so much!
というわけでですね、ここからゲストの方々がたくさんいらっしゃいます！
So, from here on, a lot of guests are going to appear!
もうホロメンだけでも多分尾丸ポルカ史上最大のゲスト数だと思っております！
I think this might be the largest number of guests in Omaru Polka history just among Holomem!
それをね、これからノンストップでお送りするので楽しんでいってください！というわけで、行くぞー！
We'll be delivering it non-stop from here on, so please enjoy! And with that, let's go!
眠りレベルの
Sleeping-level...
インディペンデント
independent
絶望も希望も抱いて あがけ命尽きるまで
Embrace despair and hope, struggle until life runs out
ひっそりと息吹くの
Breathing quietly,
恋のような虹のバスで
on a rainbow bus like love.
どんな美しい日も
No matter how beautiful the days,
何か生まれ 何かが死ぬ
something is born, something dies.
せめて歌を
At least let me sing a song,
I love you 世界がひどい地獄だとしても
I love you, even if the world is a terrible hell.
せめて伝えよう
At least let me convey it,
I love you 大解放の 時は来た 星降る
I love you, the time of liberation has come, shooting stars...
天へと響きとべリバディソング
resound to the heavens, everybody sing!
スターダスト
Stardust.
そして奇跡は待つものじゃなくて
And miracles aren't things you wait for,
その手で作るものとほほえめ
but things you create with your own hands, so smile.
涙した過去をこの願いをレクイエムにして
Turn your tearful past and this wish into a requiem,
淀みあるぜんぶの力で
with all your turbid strength.
この夜景 フューチャーは信じて果てさせ星天ギャラクシィクロス
Believe in this night's future and bring it to an end, Seiten Galaxy Cross!
ひとりじゃないことを
That you're not alone,
やがて君は知る日のため 指先伝うはしろう
for the day you will eventually know it, trace it with your fingertips.
分かち合って明日に向かう
Sharing and heading towards tomorrow,
永遠なる空に I feel you
in the eternal sky, I feel you.
自由の魂は 孤独をせわしない
The soul of freedom doesn't rush loneliness.
名もなき夢に I feel you 星へと手を握れ 運命も終局も断ち切る力で
In a nameless dream, I feel you. Clench your hand toward the stars, with the power to cut through fate and the finale.
そして刻まれた夢
And the engraved dream...
遺伝子レベルのインディペンデント
Independent on a genetic level,
絶望も希望も抱いて
embracing both despair and hope.
足掻き 命尽きるまで
Struggling until life runs out,
ヒカリと飛沫のkiss
a kiss of light and spray,
恋のような 虹のバースデイ
like love, a rainbow birthday.
神様も知らない 歴史が光り 踊る
A history shines and dances, unknown even to God.
マイサバイブ brave hearts
My survive, brave hearts!
星天ギャラクシィクロスク
Seiten Galaxy Cross!
夜空の翼で
With the wings of the night sky,
Yes, just believe
不死なる炎で ignition
through undying flames, ignition...
過去を背負い戦おう
let's fight carrying the past.
そして奇跡は待つモノじゃなくて…謳え！
And miracles aren't things you wait for... sing out!
何度だって 何度だって 立ち上がろうか！
No matter how many times, let's stand back up!
生残る全てのチカラで 輝け future world
With the power of all living things, shine, future world!
信じ 照らせ
Believe and illuminate,
星天ギャラクシィクロスク
Seiten Galaxy Cross!
聖なる全の力で
With the sacred power of all,
輝け future world 信じ照らせ
shine, future world, believe and illuminate—
星天ギャラクシィクロスク
Seiten Galaxy Cross!
咲かせたい トリオドリーム
Trio dreams we want to make bloom,
Let's sing! Let's spin! Let's dance! Let's born! Let's smile! Let's fly!
Speak your dream! Let's sing! Let's spin! Let's dance! Let's born! Let's smile! Let's fly!
出逢いかわして 世界未来
Exchanging encounters, a world of future.
1＋1＋1は無限
1 + 1 + 1 is infinity,
唇からこぼれる歌は
and the song spilling from our lips
ラララ…
is la la la...
プリズム眩しい光
A dazzling prism of light.
三人寄れば文殊の才でしょ？
Three heads are better than one, right?
始まる ザ・イチ・ト・ノ・ラ・グ Enjoy Together
Let's enjoy together the one and only!
時めき高鳴りハーモニー
Throbbing, pounding harmony,
ジャ・ゾ・ク 感性ね
jazzy, emotional,
好端レスポンス 輝きでいいよね
high-end response, shining is just fine, right?
好きだ 好きだ 思い切り叫ぼう
I love it, I love it, let's shout it out with all our might!
フレーズを心象に 夢の設定 君あなたの元へ
Imprint the phrase into our hearts, setting of dreams, to you—to your side!
もっともっと 輝き合えるね みんなで
We can shine even brighter together, everyone!
瞳作りに いつだって 笑顔映し合おう
In making our eyes, let's always reflect each other's smiles.
君がいるからほら 生まれるよ今日も
Because you're here, look, today is born anew too.
咲かせたい トリオドリーム Let's sing! Let's spin! Let's dance! Let's born! Let's smile! Let's fly!
Trio dreams we want to make bloom! Let's sing, spin, dance, born, smile, fly!
Speak your dream! Let's sing! Let's spin! Let's dance! Let's born! Let's smile! Let's fly!
Speak your dream! Let's sing, spin, dance, born, smile, fly!
一緒だから感じるハッピー
Feeling happy because we're together,
1×1×1は無限大
1 x 1 x 1 is infinity.
出し惜しみはなしで全部上げたい
I want to give you everything without holding back anything.
パフォーマンスさえもちょっとワンダフル
Even our performance is a bit wonderful.
三人寄れば文殊も凌ぐ天才
Three heads surpass even Monju, a genius!
見せるよきっと伝説のライクアンコールちょうだい
We'll show you for sure, give us your legendary like & encore!
ゆるみ糸 ポコポポ ポンプ シャンソン
Loose thread, poco-popo pump, chanson,
オールジャンルウェルカム
all-genre welcome!
カテゴリライズいらないね 好きだ 好きだ
We don't need categorization, I love it, I love it!
思い切り心音の羽広げ 果てなき奥へ
Open wide the wings of our heartbeats, towards the endless depths.
一つの命は 輝きでできて いるの？
Is a single life made of radiance?
綺麗のビズスクリーモ はみ出しちゃう
Screaming out our beauty, overflowing,
嬉しいや楽しい ファースト
happy and fun, first!
君を知って 知らない自分に出会えたよ
Knowing you, I met a self I didn't know.
咲かせたい トリオドリーム
Trio dreams we want to make bloom!
Let's sing! Let's spin! Let's dance! Let's born! Let's smile! Let's fly!
君も一緒に！Let's sing! Let's spin! Let's dance! Let's born! Let's smile! Let's fly!
Together with you too! Let's sing, spin, dance, born, smile, fly!
輝きでいいよね 好きだ 好きだ
Shining is just fine, I love it, I love it!
フレーズを心象に 夢の設定 君あなたの元へ
Imprint the phrase into our hearts, setting of dreams, to you—to your side!
もっともっと 輝き合えるね みんな！
We can shine even brighter together, everyone!
ひとすじの いつまでも 笑顔映し合おう
A single stream... let's always reflect each other's smiles.
キミがいるからパワ 生まれるよ今日も
Because you're here, power is born today too!
Let's fly! Let's try!
Let's speed!
Let's dance!
Let's bounce!
Let's smile!
Let's try!
Let's fly! Let's try!
Let's speed!
Let's dance!
Let's bounce!
Let's smile!
Let's try!
Awakening Harmony
[Title: Awakening Harmony]
作詞：こだまさおり 作曲：田代みきし
暗闇の真ん中 真っ直ぐなまなざしで
Right in the middle of the darkness, with a straight gaze,
立ち上がる姿 ちゃんと見ていたよ
I was watching you stand up properly.
閉じ込められそうな心を奮い立たせ
Rousing the heart that seemed about to be locked away,
おさまりきらない輝きを放ち
emitting a brilliance that cannot be contained.
射抜かれた胸の奥 焼き付いた目映さは
Deep in the pierced heart, the burnt-in radiance—
それだけでもう理由になる 待っていて
That alone is already reason enough. Wait for me.
取り戻したい光の世界
The world of light we want to take back,
その笑顔 勇気 涙 夢 希望の兆し
that smile, courage, tears, dreams, signs of hope,
キミと明日を願うチカラで 生まれる私達のハーモニー
with the power to wish for tomorrow with you, our harmony is born.
響け それでも暗闇は訪れてしまうもの
Resonate! Still, darkness is something that visits us,
惑わされないで キミはキミだから
so don't be misled, because you are you.
渡しあえた日々がハートを輝かせ
The days we shared make our hearts shine,
ひとりじゃないこと 気づかせてくれる
making us realize we're not alone.
抱えきれないほどの“ありがとう”の代わりに
Instead of the 'thank you's that I can't hold anymore,
鍵をかけてひとつになる 受け止めて
let's lock them away and become one. Please accept me.
取り戻すんだ光の未来 今アツイ想い繋ぐ声 叶えに行くよ
We will take back the future of light, now connecting burning feelings and voices, going to fulfill them.
キミと一緒に願う奇跡 かさねて広がっていくハーモニー
The miracle I wish for together with you, our harmony overlapping and spreading far and wide.
目覚める時が来たね ホントの自分になる 満ちる運命
The time to awaken has come, becoming your true self, a fulfilling destiny.
取り戻したい光の世界 その笑顔 勇気 涙 夢 希望の兆し
The world of light we want to take back—that smile, courage, tears, dreams, signs of hope,
キミと明日を願うチカラで 生まれる私達のハーモニー
with the power to wish for tomorrow with you, our harmony is born.
響け それでも暗闇は訪れてしまうもの 惑わされないで キミはキミだから
Resonate! Still, darkness is something that visits us, so don't be misled, because you are you.
私出会えた日々がハートを輝かせて
The days we met make our hearts shine,
ひとりじゃないこと 気づかせてくれる
making us realize we're not alone.
抱えきれないほどの ありがとうの代わりに
Instead of the 'thank you's that I can't hold anymore,
目覚める時が来たね ホントの自分になる
The time to awaken has come, becoming your true self.
満ちる運命 取り戻したい光の世界
A fulfilling destiny, the world of light we want to take back.
その笑顔 勇気 涙 夢 希望の兆し
That smile, courage, tears, dreams, signs of hope,
キミと明日を願うチカラで 生まれる私達のハーモニー
with the power to wish for tomorrow with you, our harmony is born.
響け それでも暗闇は訪れてしまうもの
Resonate! Still, darkness is something that visits us,
惑わされないで キミはキミだから
so don't be misled, because you are you.
私出会えた日々がハートを輝かせて
The days we met make our hearts shine,
ひとりじゃないこと 気づかせてくれる
making us realize we're not alone.
抱えきれないほどの ありがとうの代わりに
Instead of the 'thank you's that I can't hold anymore,
鍵をかけてひとつになる 受け止めて
let's lock them away and become one. Please accept me.
トライアングル・ドリーマー
[Title: Triangle Dreamer]
作詞・作曲：烏屋茶坊
day by day 日に日に 募るの 乙女心
Day by day, my maiden heart grows fonder,
おなじクラス
in the same class...
day by day 日に日に募るの 乙女心
Day by day, my maiden heart grows fonder
おんなじクラス斜め前の おとなしい人
The quiet guy diagonally across in the same class
カッコ良くはない だけど優しい
Not that cool, but kind
いつも 頼れる 彼
Always someone I can rely on
after school 恋愛相談の 帰り道
After school, on the way home from asking for advice
なんだって話せる 親友の女の子
My best girl friend who I can talk to about anything
スポーツ万能 勉強もできて
Good at sports, good at studying too
女子力 max です
And her girl power is at max!
どこにでもある よくあること
It happens everywhere, it happens all the time
急に彼女が「あのね、実は私 好きな人がいるの…！」って ちょっと マジで！？
When she suddenly says, "You know, actually... there's someone I like!" Wait, seriously!?
三角形 三角形 の 恋 は きまぐれ
Triangle, triangular love is fickle
一瞬で 一瞬で くずれる バランス
In an instant, the balance collapses
ベタなマンガみたいなフラグ
Like a cliché manga flag
まさか自分が立てちゃうなんて
Never thought I'd be the one to set it up
残念すぎます！
What a shame!
三角形 三角形 の 恋 は 不安定
Triangle, triangular love is unstable
なんちゃって なんちゃって じゃ済まない カテゴリー
A category where "just kidding" won't cut it
恋と友情 ゆらゆらめいて なんか青春しちゃいます わたし困っちまい ます
Love and friendship waver, feeling so youthful, I'm in trouble
完璧です！お似合いすぎるわ 勝てっこない
Perfect! You two are too good a match, I can't win
くやしいけど とかそんなんじゃなくて 本心
Not out of frustration or anything, but from the bottom of my heart
ってゆうか既に 応援モード むしろ清々しい
If anything, I'm already in support mode, feeling quite refreshed
だけれど彼女は不思議な顔
Yet she gives me a strange look
真剣な目で「そうじゃなくて、私 あなたが好き…ゴメン」って ちょっとマジで！？
With serious eyes: "It's not that, I like you... sorry." Wait, seriously!?
三角形 三角形 の 恋 は きまぐれ
Triangle, triangular love is fickle
一瞬で 一瞬で くずれる バランス
In an instant, the balance collapses
わたし アナタ 彼女 と わたし 超絶 ！ 複雑 ！ 百合展開 は 想定外 です ！
Me, you, her and me—such an absurd, complex Yuri development is totally unexpected!
三角形 三角形 の 恋 は 不安定
Triangle, triangular love is unstable
なんちゃって なんちゃって じゃ済まない カテゴリー
A category where "just kidding" won't cut it
解けない パズル 与えたもうた 神 よ 恨んじまい ます わたし悩んじまい ます
You gave me an unsolvable puzzle, oh God, I blame you and I'm so worried
「あーっ！もう！すごいヤバい！」
Oh man, this is so crazy!
「好きだよ？好きだけど…って、そういう意味じゃなくって！」
I like you? I like you, but... that's not what I meant!
「だって…女の子同士だし…」
Because... we're both girls...
「ねえ神様、どうしたらいいの？」
Hey God, what should I do?
「わたし、どうしたいの？」
What do I even want?
「ヘルプミ～～～！！！」
Help meee!!!
なんか変だー 愛に国境も 歳も 性別も カンケーない！
Something's weird, love knows no borders, age, or gender!
三角形 三角形 の 恋 は きまぐれ 一瞬で 一瞬で くずれる バランス
Triangle, triangular love is fickle, the balance collapses in an instant
普通の恋 夢見てたのに ノーマル設定のわたし じゃちょっと無理ゲーすぎます！
I was dreaming of a normal romance, but for normal-setting me, this game is way too hard!
三角形 三角形 の 恋 は 不安定 なんちゃって なんちゃって じゃ済まない カテゴリー 彼女のこと 好きになれたら なんて妄想しちゃいます わたしどうかしてます
Triangle, triangular love is unstable, a category where "just kidding" won't cut it, if I could fall in love with her, I start imagining things, I'm losing my mind
「あ、もう、すごいヤバい！」
Oh, man, this is so crazy!
「見たよ、見たけど…っ！そういう意味じゃなくて！」
I saw it, I saw it, but... that's not what I meant!
「だって、女の子同士だし…」
Because, we're both girls...
「ねえ神様、どうしたらいいの？」
Hey God, what should I do?
「私、どうしたいの？」
What do I even want?
「ヘルプミーーー！！！」
Help meee!!!
なんか変だー 愛に国境も 歳も 性別も カンケーない！ だけど、だけど、だけど！
Something's weird, love knows no borders, age, or gender! But, but, but!
三角形 三角形 の 恋 は きまぐれ 一瞬で 一瞬で くずれる バランス
Triangle, triangular love is fickle, the balance collapses in an instant
普通の恋 夢見てたのに ノーマル設定のわたし じゃちょっと無理ゲーすぎます！
I was dreaming of a normal romance, but for normal-setting me, this game is way too hard!
三角形 三角形 の 恋 は 不安定 なんちゃって なんちゃって じゃ済まない カテゴリー
Triangle, triangular love is unstable, a category where "just kidding" won't cut it
彼女のこと 好きになれたら なんて妄想しちゃいます わたしどうかしてます
If I could fall in love with her, I start imagining things, I'm losing my mind
三角形 三角形 の 恋 は きまぐれ 一瞬で 一瞬で くずれる バランス
Triangle, triangular love is fickle, the balance collapses in an instant
普通の恋 夢見てたのに ノーマル設定のわたし じゃちょっと無理ゲーすぎます！
I was dreaming of a normal romance, but for normal-setting me, this game is way too hard!
三角形 三角形 の 恋 は 不安定 なんちゃって なんちゃって じゃ済まない カテゴリー
Triangle, triangular love is unstable, a category where "just kidding" won't cut it
彼女のこと 好きになれたら なんて妄想しちゃいます わたしどうかしてます
If I could fall in love with her, I start imagining things, I'm losing my mind
わたし どうか し て ます
I'm losing my mind...
劫々とつづく
Glowing continuously,
ショート・ショット
short shots.
喪失は絶対零度だ
Loss is absolute zero.
今夜はリンカネーション
Tonight is reincarnation,
哀しみが混沌の子守唄うたってるよ
sadness sings a lullaby of chaos.
運命に理由があるのならば
If fate has a reason,
すべてを賭けてみたいの
I want to wager everything on it.
あなたを守りたい
I want to protect you.
どこまでも高く飛べるわ
I can fly high anywhere.
どこまでも強く強くなれるわ
I can grow stronger and stronger anywhere.
信じて わたしに出会えた奇跡
Believe in the miracle of meeting me.
切り開くのは、不死鳥の炎
What cuts open is the phoenix's flame.
説いて あなたのドグマ
Explain your dogma.
blackout blackout
眼差したいしたくなるの
Bare and stripped, I want to go barefoot.
flashback flashback
振りほどけ
Shake it off,
ascend
挑み続けろ
keep challenging.
飄々とたたずむ ホット・ショット
Calmly standing, hot shots.
わたしが必要でしょ?
Do you need me?
今夜はリンカネーション 正しさがストレイシープ最前線に押し出すよ
Tonight is reincarnation, righteousness pushes the stray sheep to the front lines.
運命に理由があるのならば
If fate has a reason,
優しい世界をあげたい
I want to give you a gentle world.
あなたを包むわ どこまでも速く射抜くわ
I will wrap around you, shooting swiftly anywhere.
どこまでも熱く熱く焦がすわ
Scorching hot and burning anywhere.
信じて わたしに出会えた奇跡
Believe in the miracle of meeting me.
切り開くのは、不死鳥の炎
What cuts open is the phoenix's flame.
説いて あなたのドグマ
Explain your dogma.
blackout blackout
肩越しに光を見せて
Show me the light over your shoulder.
flashback flashback
許さない
I won't forgive you,
betray
進み続けろ 尽きるまで
keep advancing until the end.
傍にいると 鼓動が速くて 目眩がする
Being by your side makes my heart beat fast and dizziness takes over.
全て捧げる もう決めたの 最後のチャンスだからもう離さないで
I offer everything, I've already decided, it's my last chance so I won't let go anymore.
どこまでも高く飛べるわ どこまでも強く強くなれるわ
I can fly high anywhere, I can grow stronger and stronger anywhere.
信じて わたしに出会えた奇跡 切り開くのは、不死鳥の炎
Believe in the miracle of meeting me, what cuts open is the phoenix's flame.
説いて あなたのドグマ
Explain your dogma.
blackout blackout
眼差したいしたくなるの
I want to gaze at you.
flashback flashback
振りほどけ
Shake it off,
ascend
挑み続けろ
keep challenging.
艶々とたたずむ ホット・ショット わたしが必要でしょ?
Glossily standing, hot shots. Do you need me?
もう離さない あなたに燃ゆる 未来の風は 逆らっていけ
I won't let go anymore, the future wind burning for you, go against it.
どこまでも高く飛べるわ どこまでも強く強くなれるわ
I can fly high anywhere, I can grow stronger and stronger anywhere.
信じて わたしに出会えた奇跡 切り開くのは、不死鳥の炎
Believe in the miracle of meeting me, what cuts open is the phoenix's flame.
説いて あなたのドグマ
Explain your dogma.
blackout blackout
肩越しに光を見せて
Show me the light over your shoulder.
flashback flashback
許さない
I won't forgive you,
betray
進み続けろ 尽きるまで
keep advancing until the end.
髪よ望めば 輝かにするから どこまでも速く射抜くわ
If you wish for hair to shine, I will shoot swiftly anywhere.
どこまでも熱く熱く焦がすわ どこまでも強く強くなれるわ
Scorching hot and burning anywhere, I can grow stronger and stronger anywhere.
信じて わたしに出会えた奇跡 切り開くのは、不死鳥の炎
Believe in the miracle of meeting me, what cuts open is the phoenix's flame.
説いて あなたのドグマ
Explain your dogma.
blackout blackout
裸々裸々 裸足になりたくな るの
Bare and stripped, I want to go barefoot.
flashback flashback
振りほどけ
Shake it off,
ascend
挑み続けろ 尽きるまで
keep challenging until the end.
傍にいると 鼓動が速くて 目眩がする
Being by your side makes my heart beat fast and dizziness takes over.
全て捧げる もう決めたの
I offer everything, I've already decided.
神様に恋をしていた頃は
When I was in love with God,
こんな別れが来るとは思っていなかったよ
I never thought such a parting would come.
もう二度と触れられないなら
If I could never touch you again,
せめて最後に もう一度抱きしめて欲しかったよ
at least for the last time, I wanted to be held once more.
It's long long good-bye...
さよなら さよなら 何度だって自分に 無上言い聞かせて
Goodbye, goodbye, over and over again I tell myself.
手を振るのは 優しさだよね？
Waving my hand is kindness, right?
今 強さが欲しい
Now, I want strength.
It's long long good-bye...
さようなら さようなら 何度だって
Goodbye, goodbye, no matter how many times,
自分に 無情に 生きかせて
living so ruthlessly to myself...
手を振るのは 優しさだよね...
Waving my hand is kindness, right?
今 強さが欲しい
Now I want strength.
貴方に出会い STAR輝いて
I encountered you, the star shone brightly,
アタシが生まれて
and I was born.
愛せばこそ iがあればこそ
Indeed if I love, indeed if there's 'I',
希望のない 奇跡を待って
waiting for a hopeless miracle,
どうなるの？
what will become of me?
涙に滲む 惑星の瞬きは...
The twinkle of planets stained with tears is gone...
忘れないよ 貴方の温もりも
I won't forget your warmth,
その優しさも 全て包んでくれた両手も
and your kindness, and both hands that surrounded everything.
It's long long good-bye...
さようなら さようなら
Goodbye, goodbye,
愛しい人
beloved one.
貴方がいたから
Because you were there,
歩いてこれた
I was able to walk here.
ひとりなんかじゃなかったよね？
I wasn't alone, right?
今 答えが欲しい
Now I want the answer.
燃えるような流星 捕まえて
Catch the burning meteors
火を灯して
and light the fire.
愛していたい 愛されていたい
I want to love, I want to be loved.
冷えたカラダひとつで
With a single chilled body,
世界はどうなるの？
what will become of the world?
張り続けてた 虚勢が溶けていく long for...
The bravado I kept up is melting away, long for...
どうしてなの？ 涙溢れて
What's the matter? Tears overflow
止められない
and I can't stop them.
貴方に出会い STAR輝いて
I encountered you, the star shone brightly,
アタシが生まれて
and I was born.
愛せばこそ iがあればこそ
Indeed if I love, indeed if there's 'I',
希望のない 奇跡を待って
waiting for a hopeless miracle,
どうなるの？
what will become of me?
涙に滲む 惑星の瞬きは...
The twinkle of planets stained with tears is gone...
もし生れ変わって また巡り会えるなら
If I am reborn and we can meet again,
その時もきっと アタシを見つけ出して
surely you'll find me then.
もう二度と離さないで 捕まえてて...
Don't ever let go of me again, catch me...
神様に恋をしていた頃は
When I was still in love with God,
こんな別れが来るとは思っていなかったよ
I never expected such a farewell would come.
もう二度と触れられないなら せめて最後に もう一度抱きしめて欲しかったよ
If I could never feel your touch again, I'd have wished to be embraced just one last time.
貴方に出会い STAR輝いて アタシが生まれて
I met you, the stars sparkled, and I was born.
愛すればこそ iあればこそ
I love you, therefore I am.
涙に染まる 惑星の瞬きは gone...
Through my tear-filled vision, the planet's twinkle is gone...
聖なる瞳が
If my saint-like eyes
痛みを映したら
emit pain,
振り返ってごらん？
will you turn away?
情熱放つTrick
A passion-releasing trick.
崩れる足元
Our crumbling pace
二人は戻れない
won't return.
差し伸べた手を ほどかないで
Don't leave me with my hand stretched out.
消えるよまた
These tender days
優しい日々が
have disappeared once again,
思い出を汚すのは 許せない
I won't allow us to have disgraced memories.
ここは裏切りの楽園
This is the paradise of betrayal.
さ迷う心の果てに
At the end of my wandering heart,
光を求めて 祈る言葉 届けあなたに
I search for a light and words of prayer I can send to you.
囚われの羽が 遥かな空へと向かう
My imprisoned wings fly towards the distant sky.
信じたいよ 私たち 孤独じゃない
I want to believe that we are not alone.
分かり合う 絆の中
We understand within this bond
離さない 始まるDestiny
We won't let go of our beginning destiny.
新たな願いに 鎖ほどける時 休ませてくれる?
When my new wish is freed from its chains, will you let me rest?
深い眠りに 微かな希望が 私を強くする
Into a deep sleep. Even a slight hope makes me stronger,
ぬくもりに触れてみたいから 蘇れば 僅かなのち
Because I want to touch your warmth. Reviving, this transient life
繰り返す愛しさが導いた
Guided by repeating affection.
胸に泡沫の調べ 流れる世界の終わり
A fleeting melody in my breast, the end of a flowing world,
諦めはしない 今が繋ぐ明日探そう
I won't give up, let's search for tomorrow connected by the present.
ちぎれ舞う羽は 未来の空へも向かう
Wings fluttering and tearing apart head towards the future sky as well.
忘れないで 私たちひとつ結晶 輝いて 割れないのよ
Don't forget, we are a single crystal. Shining, unbreakable.
離さない 誓いのDestiny
We won't let go of our sworn destiny.
消えるよまた 優しい日々が
These tender days disappear once again,
思い出を汚すのは 許せない
I won't allow us to have disgraced memories.
ここは裏切りの楽園
This is the paradise of betrayal.
さ迷う心の果てに 光を求めて 祈る言葉 届けあなたに
At the end of my wandering heart, I search for a light...
囚われの羽が 遥かな空へと向かう
My imprisoned wings fly towards the distant sky.
信じたいよ 私たち 孤独じゃない
I want to believe that we are not alone.
分かり合う 絆の中
We understand within this bond.
聖なる瞳が
From these eyes which seem of a saint
痛みを映したら
if they're ever to show honest pain,
振り向いて
will you turn away,
ごらん？
let me fall
情熱放つ Trick
to the hold of passionate tricks?
Paradise Lost
やっとみんな会えたね
At last, we're all able to meet!
don’t stop！no,don’t stop ' til finish！！
Don't stop! No, don't stop 'til finish!!
高まった全力走りたい
With heightened strength, I want to run all out!
芝と砂とキミの追い切りメニュー
Turf, sand, and your grueling final workout menu!
turn up！
Turn up!
声出せ叫べ
Raise your voices and shout!
トレセン！ファイ！ファイ！
Trecen! Fight! Fight!
高まった全力上がりタイム
With heightened strength, our final sprint time is here!
譲れない夢の途中
In the middle of an unyielding dream,
始めようここから最高story
let's start the ultimate story right here!
あこがれの地へ
To the place we've longed for,
語り合ったmemory
sharing our memories together...
もうドキドキもドキメキも抑られない
Our racing, throbbing excitement cannot be contained!
たまらない熱いハラハラが止まらない
This irresistible, passionate thrill won't stop!
キミと走り比べゴール目指し
Racing side by side with you toward the finish line,
遥か響け届けmusic
let our music echo far and wide!
ずっとずっとずっとずっと想い 夢がきっと叶うなら
If our endless, everlasting feelings and dreams are bound to come true...
あの日にキミに感じた何かを信じて
believing in something I felt in you that day,
春も夏も秋も冬も越え 願い焦がれ走れ ah勝利へ
crossing spring, summer, autumn, and winter, yearning and burning to run toward victory, ah!
don’t stop！no,don’t stop ' til finish！！
Don't stop! No, don't stop 'til finish!!
高まった全力はじめたい
With heightened strength, I want to start all out!
期待出会い決意キズナになった
Expectations, encounters, and resolutions became our bonds!
hands up！
Hands up!
本気で叫べ
Shout with all your heart!
トレセン！ファイ！ファイ！
Trecen! Fight! Fight!
高まった全力笑いたい
With heightened strength, I want to smile all out!
ターフのど真中
Right in the middle of the turf,
リアルにここから上昇story
a rising story starts for real right here!
かけぬけた日々
The days we dashed through,
語り合ったglory
sharing the glory together.
いま応えたい「生きている」と
Now I want to answer: "I am truly alive!"
背中押す声熱くなる
The voices pushing my back grow so warm.
夢は夢のまま終えれない
We can't let a dream end just as a dream!
キミと未来描きゴール目指し
Painting our future with you, aiming for the finish line,
狙え挑め掴めwinning
aim for it, challenge it, seize that winning moment!
ずっとずっとずっとずっと想い 夢がきっと叶うなら
If our endless, everlasting feelings and dreams are bound to come true...
あの日キミが流した涙も信じて
believing even in the tears you shed that day,
雨も風も雲も闇も越え 願い焦がれ走れ ah勝利へ
crossing rain, wind, clouds, and darkness, yearning and burning to run toward victory, ah!
駆け抜けた日々
The days we dashed through,
語り合ったグローリー
sharing the glory together.
今こたえたい「生きている」と
Now I want to answer: "I am truly alive!"
背中押す声熱くなる
The voices pushing my back grow so warm.
夢は夢のまま終えれない
We can't let a dream end just as a dream!
キミと未来描きゴール目指し
Painting our future with you, aiming for the finish line,
狙え挑め掴めwinning
aim for it, challenge it, seize that winning moment!
ずっとずっとずっとずっと想い 夢がきっと叶うなら
If our endless, everlasting feelings and dreams are bound to come true...
あの日キミが鳴らした
The bells you rang that day,
涙も信じて
believing in those tears too.
雨も風も雲も闇も越え願い焦がれ走れ ah勝利へ
crossing rain, wind, clouds, and darkness, yearning and burning to run toward victory, ah!
揺るぎない覚悟決して
Making an unshakable resolve,
1つ2つ共に綴る記録
recording our milestones one by one together.
背中に迫る迷い振り払え
Shake off the doubts closing in behind us,
今の自分追い越すだけ
just surpass your current self!
かちたい かちたい かちたい キミと かちたい
I want to win, win, win, I want to win with you!
未来描きゴール目指し 狙え挑め掴めwinning
Painting our future, aiming for the goal—aim, challenge, seize the win!
ずっとずっとずっとずっと想い 夢がきっと叶うなら
If our endless, everlasting feelings and dreams are bound to come true...
あの日キミが流した涙も信じて
believing in the tears you shed that day,
春も夏も秋も冬も越え 雨も風も雲も闇も越え 勝利へ
crossing spring, summer, autumn, winter, rain, wind, clouds, and darkness toward victory!
キミと走り比べゴール目指し 遥か響け届けmusic
Racing side by side with you toward the goal, let our music echo far and wide!
ずっとずっとずっとずっと想い 夢がきっと叶うなら
If our endless, everlasting feelings and dreams are bound to come true...
あの日キミに感じた何かを信じて
believing in something I felt in you that day,
夏も秋も冬も越え 願いこがれ走れ
Crossing summer, autumn, and winter, longing and running,
ああ 勝利へ
Ah, toward victory!
未来描きゴール目指し
Drawing the future, aiming for the goal,
ネライドメツカメ Winning!
Aiming, locking on, seizing the win!
ずっとずっとずっとずっと想い
Ever, ever, ever, ever wishing,
夢はきっと叶うから
Because dreams will surely come true.
あの日キミが流した
The tears you shed that day—
涙も信じて
Believe in them too.
雨も風も雲も闇も越え 願いこがれ走れ
Crossing rain, wind, clouds, and darkness, longing and running,
ああ 勝利へ
Ah, toward victory!
Don't stop! No, don't stop 'til finish!!
it's finally the true end
i'm ready for... my destiny
i'm ready for... starting over
やっと幕を下ろせた 最後の瞬間まで
Until the very final moment when the curtain finally fell,
わたしは精一杯に わたしをやりきった
I gave it my absolute all and played my part to the fullest.
終演の続きは 誰も知らなくていい
Nobody needs to know what happens after the show ends;
涙を置いて 新しい旅に出よう
Let's leave our tears behind and set off on a new journey.
熱狂はあなたを選ぶ 違う結末だっただけ
The fervor simply chose you—it was just a different ending,
同じ愛になれなかった Destiny
A Destiny that couldn't become the same love.
これまでの全てを 差し出すような愛だった
It was a love that offered up everything up to now,
世界の意味が変わるくらいに 肯定された気がしたんだ
Making me feel validated enough to change the meaning of the world.
何気なさの中で 気づけた最初の奇跡が
The very first miracle I noticed in the ordinary days was—
あなたでよかった わたしでよかった 心から思えたよ
"I'm glad it was you, I'm glad it was me"—I could truly feel that from the bottom of my heart.
ずっと遠い未来も ちゃんと覚えていよう
Let's remember clearly even far-off futures,
自分の抱きしめかた 明日の願いかた
How I held myself close, and how I wished for tomorrow.
あなたがいなくても わたしの片隅で
Even if you're not here, in a corner of my heart,
優しい光 消えたりしないとわかる
I know the gentle light will never fade away.
今はまだ手を振れるほど 道は別れたばかりで 後ろ髪に風を感じながら
Right now, having just parted ways, it's too soon to wave goodbye, while feeling the wind in my hair from behind.
それまでの全てが あなたに出会うためだった
Everything until then was so I could meet you;
どの瞬間もムダじゃないこと 本当の意味で知れたから
Because I've learned in the true sense that not a single moment was wasted,
次の曲がり角も 自分らしさで選べるはず
I should be able to choose the next corner staying true to myself.
いつかに繋がる 新しい一歩 信じて歩き出そう
Let's step forward believing in a new step that connects to someday.
心から誰かを愛せた あの日々は
Those days when I could love someone from the bottom of my heart
間違いなくわたしの Destiny Ah,
Were undoubtedly my Destiny, Ah...
これまでの全てが 新しい力をくれる
Everything up until now gives me new strength;
どの瞬間もムダじゃないなら 何が起きても大丈夫だから
If not a single moment is wasted, then whatever happens, it'll be alright,
次の物語も 自分らしさで選べるはず
So I should be able to choose the next story staying true to myself too.
いつかに繋がる わたしのはじまり 信じて歩き出そう
Let's step forward believing in my beginning that connects to someday.
いつかに繋がる　わたしのはじまり　信じて歩き出そう
Connecting someday, my beginning, let's step forward with faith.
再び幕は上がる
The curtain rises once again.
聞いていただいたのは、新曲の
What you've been listening to is her brand-new song,
「STARTING OVER」でした！
"STARTING OVER"!
はい、新年一発目、新曲の
Well, as this is the first single of the new year,
初披露というわけで、ぬるっとね、新曲をやっちまったんですが、
we smoothly went and released a brand-new track,
平成感のある、えー、懐かしみのある感じの楽曲を、こちらですね、歌わさせていただいたんですけれど、
but we've actually let you listen to a song with a very nostalgic feel to it from the Heisei era!
この後、この曲が、えっと、24時から、あともう、1時間後か、24時から、ですね、えー、1月30日の24時から、配信、リリースされます！たくさん聞いてください！
However, this song will be released 24 hours from now—well, just a few hours from now, at 24:00 on January 30th, so please listen to it a lot!
今年もね、たくさんオリジナル曲出していきたいです！
This year too, I want to release lots of original songs!
そしてそして、MCがね、実は最後なのでね、えーっと、
And what's more, since this is my final MC session,
この配信の後には、メンバー限定の配信もあるので、よろしくお願いします！
after this stream, there will be a members-only stream, so I hope you'll check that out too!
よしよしよし、お疲れ様会！
Right, right, right! Good job, everyone!
えー、ここには同期のね、ポルラボ大集合ということで、
And here we have all of our fellow gen-mates assembled together,
ねえ、ら、ぼ、集まれー！
so, um... everyone, gather around!
いえーい！　いぇーい！　いぇーい！　いぇーい！　初めて呼びました！　どうも！
Yay! Yay! Yay! Yay! This is the first time we've all called each other like this, thank you!
え、初めて？　ポルカチャンネル初です！　お誕生日おめでとう！　お誕生日おめでとう！　おめでとう！
First time? Is this the first time for Polka Channel? Happy birthday! Happy birthday! Happy birthday! Congratulations!
ありがとう！　ありがとう！
Thank you! Thank you!
ここまでが流れでございます、はい！　ずっと待ってたから、ちょっとね、紹介させていただきたいと思います。ね、出遅れちゃったね。
That's how the flow goes, so yes. We were waiting, so we wanted to introduce it while reacting to everything.
がやしたー！　はい、がやしたがやした！
We made it! Yes, we made it!
というわけで、尾丸ポルカ誕生日記念グッズ2026、ラインナップは、こちらー！
So, the Omaru Polka Birthday 2026 merchandise lineup is right here!
じゃーん！
Ta-da!
すごい！　今回もラインナップが揃っていまーす！
So, wow, this time our lineup is really complete!
というわけで、まず1つずつ紹介していきましょう！　まずは、こちら！
So, first we'll go through them one by one, shall we? First is right here!
はい、ポルカのね、初めての抱き枕カバーとなっております！
Yes, this is Polka's very first dakimakura cover!
すごーい、かわいい！
Oh, wow, that's amazing!
あれ、パンツは履いていません。あれ、パジャマじゃないですか？　え、本当に？　え、その部屋着だよ？　部屋着って寝るときとかってこういう部屋着なの？
Wait, isn't that just a shirt? It's a dress shirt, right? Wait, what? Is that a nightshirt or something?
自分のチャンネルだからやりたい放題チャンネルして！　え、ほんまにシャツで寝たら風邪引くぞ！
Wait, since it's her channel, she wants to do whatever she wants, but if you sleep in a dress shirt, you'll catch a cold!
おやばやば、マジレス！　写真撮影用かもしれないですね。
Oh, wow, seriously? You might even take photos in it!
なるほどね！
I see, I see.
というわけで、初めて抱き枕カバー出します。表が通常衣装で、裏がカレシャツになってます！　カレシャツになっていただきました！
So that's why we're releasing our first dakimakura cover, featuring the normal outfit on the front and a shirt on the back!
はい、ありがとうございます！
Yes, thank you!
そして続きまして、どん！
Moving on, boom!
こちら、歴代衣装のポルカランダムラバーストラップです！
This is the successive-outfit Polka random rubber strap!
これまでの衣装のラバーストラップ、こちらのいめね先生に描いていただきました！
These are rubber straps of all our past outfits, illustrated by Noime-sensei!
どの衣装が出るかお楽しみです。ありがとね、みんなリアクション本当に100点満点です！
I'm really looking forward to seeing which ones you get! Thank you everyone, your reactions are truly 100 out of 100!
はーい、続きまして、こちら！
Alright, moving on to this one!
どれもこれも宝物！思い出バインダー！
The "Everything is a Treasure" Memories Binder!
これですね、最近みんなも特典でチェキ風のブロマイドカードを出したりしてるから、そういうのに入れられたり、あとはホロカも入るサイズになってますので、ぜひぜひいろんな思い出にしまってください！
Lately we've been including chekifuu bromide cards with purchases, so you can put those in here, and it's also sized to fit Holoca cards, so please store all your favorite memories in it!
そして、続きましては、こちら！　ポルカのしっぽキーホルダー！
And next up is this! Polka's Tail Keychain!
一週して流行ってるからね、ポルカのしっぽ型のキーホルダー！　そう、平成レトロみたいな感じで、作っております！
Since tails are super trendy right now, we made a tail-shaped keychain in a Showa-retro kind of style!
はい、こちらも付けてください！
So please attach this as well!
そして、ボイスも出ます！　ボイスは、こちら！
And we also have voice packs! The voice pack is right here!
じゃーん！　ASMRボイスです！　はい、えっと、ま、「彼シャツポルカ、ただいまの距離。」
It's an ASMR voice pack titled: "Boyfriend's Shirt Polka: Just a Little Distance Away."
なんて今日同期呼んじゃったんだろうっていうのを一瞬思った、今、恥ずかしくなってきた！
Wait, why did I call my gen-mates today? I'm suddenly getting embarrassed right now!
ちょっと待って、と、ということで、ASMRというか、抱き枕カバーとイラストの関係があるシチュエーションになってます！
So yeah, this is an ASMR voice pack that has a connection to the dakimakura cover illustration!
はい、みんなお待たせしました！　フルセットをご購入特典になっております！
And we have a special bonus for those who purchase the full set!
こちら、チェキ風ブロマイドカード！　数量限定が直筆メッセージ、複製サイン入りになっております！
It's a Chekifuu Bromide Card, and for the quantity-limited version, it features a handwritten message and copied duplicate signature!
通常が箱押し複製サインとメッセージ入りでございます！
The regular version includes a copied duplicate signature and message.
フルセットぜひぜひ買っていただいた方には、特典ボイスとして、すやすやポルカのね、すやねぼいすというか、ねぇねぇねぇねぇ！
Be sure to buy the full set, because as a bonus voice, you'll get a whispery Polka saying: "A promise we'll always be together."
一緒に、ねえ、ねえ、ねえみたいな感じで、
Together, like "Hey, hey, hey,"
なんかちょっとそういったボイスになってて、
it's that kind of voice,
こっちもASMRになってます。
and this one is also ASMR.
よろしくお願いします！
We look forward to your support!
恥ずかしいな！
This is so embarrassing!
みんなとやるのこれ。
Doing this with everyone...
なんか、エッチな女みたいになっちゃってさー
We look like such lewd women...
すいません！
Sorry!
いいじゃん！
It's fine!
すいません、新年もね、皆さん改めてこれからもよろしくお願いします。
Sorry, Happy New Year everyone, we look forward to working with you all going forward too.
よろしくお願いします！お願いします！
We look forward to it! Yes, thank you!
というわけでね、今日はみんなで最後一緒に歌を歌うために呼んできたということで、準備していきます！
So today, since we invited everyone to sing together at the very end, let's get ready!
いきますよー！せーの！いくぞ！いえーい！
Here we go! Ready, set! Let's go! Yay!
脚本は捨てちゃおうか
Let's throw away the script,
差し向かって焼き付けろ！
and burn it straight into our memories!
アドリブの熱いパフォーマンス
A passionate improvisational performance
屋根裏を飛び出して 壮大なステージに響く
bursting out of the attic, echoing across the grand stage
特別なストーリー
with a special story.
瞼の裏には 虹が紡ぐ
Behind our eyelids, a rainbow weaves
星空のメモリー
a memory of the starry sky.
等身大の愛を込めて 想像を超える世界へ
Pouring in our lifesize love, to a world beyond imagination,
誰も知らないでしょう？
one nobody knows yet, right?
Are you ready? どんな未来か見に行こうよ
Are you ready? Let's go see what kind of future awaits—
なんて自由だ！笑っちゃうよね
how freeing, it makes you want to laugh!
ねえ ホログラムよりも先へ 誰だって置いてかないよ
Hey, heading further than holograms, leaving no one behind—
ご覧 歓声が
look, cheers
呼んでいる
are calling out.
スナップからパッと照らす
Lighting up in a snap,
人生のスポットライト
life's spotlight,
薔薇色のプレミアムショー
a rose-colored premium show—
ここが特等席よ
this is the front row!
本日は晴天なり
Today is clear skies,
天気次第のエチュード
an étude depending on the weather,
まるで絵物語 捕まえてよ
like a picture storybook, catch me—
待って ほら 待って
(Wait,) look—(Wait,)
予期できない展開に ステージは揺れる
in an unpredictable turn, the stage shakes
格別のストーリー
with an exceptional story.
耳を澄ましたら 月が踊る 雨粒のハーモニー
If you listen closely, the moon dances to a raindrops' harmony.
浮かぶふわふわな空想 暴走？底なしの本能！
Floating, fluffy daydreams—running wild? Bottomless instinct!
すべて知りたいでしょう？
You want to know everything, right?
Hey guys! 叫べ 気分は最高？
Hey guys! Shout out, is the feeling top-tier?
Come on! もっと叫べ 気分は最高？ 最高！
Come on! Shout more, is the feeling top-tier? Top-tier!
ポルカ終わるか？
Will Polka end?
終わるか？ポルカ終わるか？終わらない！It's showtime!
Will it end? Polka end? It's not ending! It's showtime!
繋いだ手離さないでなんてね
Holding hands tightly and saying "Don't let go," you know—
どうしたって重たくなっちゃって困るわ
no matter what, it gets heavy and troublesome!
いつ日かエピローグを一緒に綴ろう きっと約束よ
Let's weave our epilogue together someday, that's definitely a promise,
Life goes on!
どんな未来か見に行こうよ なんて自由だ！笑っちゃうよね
Let's go see what kind of future awaits—how freeing, it makes you want to laugh!
ねえ ホログラムよりも先へ 夢のような花舞台に感情を馳せたら
Hey, heading further than holograms, if we send our emotions to a dreamy stage,
スナップからパッと照らす
lighting up in a snap,
人生のスポットライト
life's spotlight,
薔薇色のプレミアムショー どこへだってそう挑んだ
a rose-colored premium show—challenging it wherever we go,
ここが特等席よ
this is the front row!
あんたじゃもう耐えない
With no time to even catch my breath,
あたしゃ本当ナイスボディボディボディ
I've been running through.
自分でゆーくらい
With no time to even think,
ただじゃないじゃないじゃない？
I moved on pure instinct.
寒さ背負うんさ寂しげにえみボディボディボディ
With no time to even catch my breath,
誰にもわかんない恋愛っていつ日がつくのか
I've been running through.
恋いまダイナマイト
With no time to even think,
I moved on pure instinct.
どんなに不機嫌だって恋は一方通行
With no time to even catch my breath,
こんなに優しくされちゃミッドナイト明るい未来に
I've been running through.
就職希望はうおうおうおう日本、未来は…
With no time to even think,
世界がうらやむ恋をしようじゃないか
I moved on pure instinct.
ダダシを大人し
With no time to even catch my breath,
何度でも物足りないどこにだって愛しててほしいは
I've been running through.
自分で伝えるの恥ずかしいじゃない？
With no time to even think,
理想の二人だが憧れよエビボディボディボディ
I moved on pure instinct.
誰しも気づいてない恋愛って夢のおとしあなミステリー
With no time to even catch my breath,
恋はミステリーこんなの不自然だって恋のインサイダー
I've been running through.
それでも上手にされちゃあらわしあわせ黒ひも
With no time to even think,
キャンセル街なのあんたの笑顔は
I moved on pure instinct.
世界がうらやむ夢があるじゃないか
With no time to even catch my breath,
ダダシを大人し
I've been running through.
何度でも物足りないどこにだって愛しててほしいは自分で伝えるの恥ずかしいじゃない？
With no time to even think,
理想の二人だが憧れよエビボディボディボディ
I moved on pure instinct.
誰しも気づいてない恋愛って夢のおとしあなミステリー
With no time to even catch my breath,
恋はミステリーこんなの不自然だって恋のインサイダー
I've been running through.
それでも上手にされちゃあらわしあわせ黒ひも
With no time to even think,
キャンセル街なのあんたの笑顔は
I moved on pure instinct.
世界がうらやむ夢があるじゃないか
With no time to even catch my breath,
ダダシを大人し
I've been running through.
何度でも物足りないどこにだって愛しててほしいは自分で伝えるの恥ずかしいじゃない？
With no time to even think,
理想の二人だが憧れよエビボディボディボディ
I moved on pure instinct.
誰しも気づいてない恋愛って夢のおとしあなミステリー
With no time to even catch my breath,
恋はミステリーこんなの不自然だって恋のインサイダー
I've been running through.
それでも上手にされちゃあらわしあわせ黒ひも
With no time to even think,
キャンセル街なのあんたの笑顔は
I moved on pure instinct.
世界がうらやむ夢があるじゃないか
With no time to even catch my breath,
ダダシを大人し
I've been running through.
何度でも物足りないどこにだって愛しててほしいは自分で伝えるの恥ずかしいじゃない？
With no time to even think,
新曲のお披露目あり！ Glitter Love
New song reveal: Glitter Love!
1/30 21:00〜
January 30, 21:00~
ポルカのライブ過去最多 ホロメンゲスト10名
Most guests in Polka's live history: 10 Hololive members!